Desert Botanical Laboratory of the Carnegie Institution records, 1903-1985
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
Desert Botanical Laboratory of the Carnegie Institution records, 1903-1985
AZ 356
This collection contains chiefly correspondence, along with reports, minutes of meetings, and financial records related to the establishment, development, and operation of the Desert Laboratory and Coastal Laboratory under directors Daniel T. MacDougal and Forrest Shreve.
Desert Botanical Laboratory of the Carnegie Institution
4 linear feet
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections University of Arizona PO Box 210055 Tucson, AZ 85721-0055 Phone: 520-621-6423 Fax: 520-621-9733 URL: http://speccoll.library.arizona.edu/
Restrictions
None.
Historical Note
The Desert Botanical Laboratory of the Carnegie Institution was established by Volney M. Spaulding and William A. Cannon at Tumamoc Hill, Tucson, Arizona, in 1903. It was sold to the U.S. Forest Service in 1940, and later to the University of Arizona in 1960. The purpose of the laboratory was to research the of adaptation of desert plants to their environment. The Laboratory was directed by D.T. MacDougal from 1906 to 1918, then by Forrest Shreve from 1929 to 1938.
By 1920, a related institution, the Coastal Laboratory was established in Carmel, California with MacDougal as director.
Organization
This collection is organized into seven series:
Series I: Carnegie Institution Officials Records and Correspondence, 1903-1938
Series II: Desert Laboratory Records and Correspondence, 1905-1937
Series III: Coastal Laboratory Correspondence, 1910-1938
Series IV: General Records and Correspondence, 1905-1938
Series V: D. T. MacDougal Personal Papers, 1908-1935
Series VI: Forrest Shreve Personal Papers, 1916-1937
Series VII: Desert Botanical Laboratory Plot Records, 1906-1985
Scope and Content Note
This collection contains chiefly correspondence, along with reports, minutes of meetings, and financial records related to the establishment, development, and operation of the Desert Laboratory and Coastal Laboratory under directors Daniel T. MacDougal and Forrest Shreve. Correspondents include Carnegie Institution officials, the Smithsonian Institution, laboratory staff members Godfrey Sykes and Herman A. Spoehr, Frederick S. Dellenbaugh, William Boyce Thompson, Andrew E. Douglass, and Mary Austin, as well as societies, herbariums, and universities around the world. Additional correspondence relates to equipment, scientific societies, plant exchanges and collecting, the University of Arizona, and personal material of both Shreve and MacDougal.
Access Terms
Shreve, Forrest, 1878-1950; MacDougal, Daniel Trembly, 1865-1958; Sykes, Godfrey, 1861-1948 -- Correspondence; Spoehr, Herman Augustus, 1885-1954 -- Correspondence; Dellenbaugh, Frederick Samuel, 1853-1935 -- Correspondence; Thompson, William Boyce, 1869-1930 -- Correspondence; Austin, Mary Hunter, 1868-1934 -- Correspondence; Douglass, A. E. (Andrew Ellicott), 1867-1962 -- Correspondence; Desert Botanical Laboratory of the Carnegie Institution -- Archives; Carnegie Institution of Washington; Carnegie Institution of Washington. Coastal Laboratory; University of Arizona -- History; Desert plants -- Arizona; Desert plants -- Sonoran Desert; Desert ecology -- Arizona; Desert ecology -- Sonoran Desert; Plant ecology -- Arizona; Plant ecologists -- Correspondence; Botanists -- Correspondence; Botanical laboratories -- Arizona -- Tucson -- History -- Sources; Botanical laboratories -- California -- Carmel -- History -- Sources; Sonoran Desert -- Research; Tumamoc Hill (Ariz.); Correspondence
Separated Material
Slides received with the collection were removed and cataloged separately.
Related Material
A related collection of D. T. MacDougal Papers can be found at the Arizona Historical Society, MS0452.
Container List
- Series I: Carnegie Institution Officials Records and Correspondence, 1903-1938
  - Reports. 1905-1906, 1909 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Minutes of Executive Meeting. January 18, 1910 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence: Woodward, R. S. (President). 1905-1913 (Box 1, Folder 2-9)
  - Correspondence: Woodward, R. S. (President). 1914-1916, 1920 (Box 2, Folder 1-2)
  - Correspondence: Merriam, John C. (President). ca. 1914, 1920-1937 (Box 2, Folder 3-8)
  - Correspondence: MacDougal, D. T. and Shreve, Forrest. 1913-1937 (Box 2, Folder 9-11)
  - Correspondence: Baker, Marcus (Assistant Secretary). August 10, 1903-October 12, 1903 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence: Gilbert, Walter M. (Assistant Secretary, Administrative Secretary). 1905-1937 (Box 3, Folder 2-10)
  - Correspondence: Wirt, John L. (Bursar). 1905-1917, 1920-1924 (Box 4, Folder 1-6)
  - Correspondence: Wirt, John L. and Varela, E. A. (Bursar) 1925-1937 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence: Barnum, William (Chief Clerk, Editor, Division of Publications). 1904-1916 (Box 4, Folder 8-9)
  - Correspondence: Barnum, William and Bunker, Frank F. (Editors, Division of Publications). 1920-1928 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence: Bunker, Frank F. (Editor, Division of Publications). 1929-1938 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Alcohol Reports and Orders. 1915-1916, 1925-1937 (Box 5, Folder 1-3)
  - Financial Statements, Notes, "Budget Items." 1907-1930 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Wage Accounts. March 1928-December 1929 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Petty Cash Account. 1928-1929 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Purchase Orders. October 1927-December 1929 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence and Records: Fifth Avenue Bank, New York. 1910-1928 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence: Southern Arizona Bank and Trust Co. 1911-1936 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Records: Southern Arizona Bank & Trust Co. 1928-1936 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence: Rose, J. N. (Smithsonian Institution, Research Associate with the Carnegie Institution, 1912-1921, and Associate Curator, Division of Plants, U. S. National Museum, 1922-1928). 1912-1928 (Box 6, Folder 1-5)
- Series II: Desert Laboratory Records and Correspondence, 1905-1937
  - Correspondence: Laboratory construction, telephone, etc. 1910-1931 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence: Arizona State Land Commission, Taxes, Forest Service. 1913-1934 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence: Breitenbecher, J. K. (Staff). 1910, 191520 1920-1925 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence: Krieger, L. C. C. (Staff). 1915 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence: Leamon, William G. (Staff). 1916 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence: Waller, J. C. (Staff). 1916, 1925 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence: Minzey, J. H. (Staff). 1927-1928 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence: Kenny, Richard (Staff). 1933 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence: Hinckley, Arthur (Staff). 1934 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence: Bovee, B. R. (Staff). 1914, 1920-1930 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence: Cannon, W. A. (Staff). 1905, 1915-1934 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence: Fraps, Mason (Staff). 1926-1936 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence: Mallery, T. D. (Staff). 1929-1936 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence: Runyon, E. H. (Staff). 1928-1937 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence: Sinclair, J. G. (Staff). 1913-1915 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence: Spalding, V. M. and Spalding, Effie, S. 1913-1932 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence: Tower, W. L. (Staff). 1912-1924 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence: Turnage, William V. (Staff). 1935-1937 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence: Working, E. B. (Staff). 1920-1937 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence: Sykes, Godfrey (Staff). (Box 8, Folder 1-7)
  - Correspondence: Sykes, Stanley, Gilbert and Glenton. 1920-1936 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence: Strickland, J. C. (Office Secretary). 1911-1915 (Box 9, Folder 1-3)
  - Correspondence: Strickland, J. C., Huber, Rena, and Gillies, E. (Office Secretaries). 1916-1920 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence: Huber, Rena (Office Secretary). 1921 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence: Huber, Rena, Maguire, Mary, Mrs. Strickland (Office Secretaries). 1922-1924 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence: Bois, R. S. (Office Secretary). 1925-1926 (Box 9, Folder 7-8)
  - Correspondence: Keddington, Mrs. Iva and others (Office Secretaries). 1927-1937 (Box 9, Folder 9)
- Series III: Coastal Laboratory Correspondence, 1910-1938
  - Correspondence: Laboratory construction, land, etc. 1912-1925 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence: Pestell, W. A. (Office). 1927-1937 (Box 10, Folder 2-6)
  - Correspondence: Aucourt, Harry (Staff). 1920-1929 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence: Ballou, Fremont O. (Staff). 1925-1933 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence: Haasis, Ferdinand W. (Staff). 1930-1935 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence: McGee, J. M. (Staff). 1916-1924 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence: McLean, F. T. (Staff). 1920-1928 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence: Tag, Tessie (Staff). 1914-1915 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence: Dutra, J. (Staff). 1916 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence: Cherry, C. W. (Staff). 1920-1921 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence: Goold, C. O. (Staff). 1920-1921 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence: Ridgway, J. L. (Staff). 1921 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence: Newton, William (Staff). 1924-1926 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence: Daugherty, L. (Staff). 1924 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence: Mawdsley, P. (Staff). 1925 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence: Wilbur, P. C. (Staff). 1925-1928 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence: Young, W. G. (Staff). 1925-1928 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence: Immink, D. H. 1927-1929 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence: G. Stieglitz and A. Smith (University of Chicago) regarding H. A. Spoehr. 1910 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence: Spoehr, H. A. (Staff). 1913-1938 (Box 11, Folder 2-9)
- Series IV: General Records and Correspondence, 1905-1938
  - Records and Correspondence of Other Institutions and Research Divisions, 1905-1937
    - Correspondence: Clements, F. E., Alpine Laboratory, Manitou, Colorado. 1913, 1920-1927 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence: Lotfield, G., Alpine Laboratory, Manitou, Colorado. 1921-1922 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence: Kidder, A. V., Division of Historical Research, Andover, Massachusetts. 1934-1935 (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence: Scott, Donald, Division of Historical Research, Andover, Massachusetts. 1935-1936 (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence: Hall, Harvey M., Division of Plant Biology, Stanford University, California. 1924-1931 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence: Smith, James H.C., Division of Plant Biology, Stanford University, California. 1924-1937 (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence: Harris, J. Arthur, Station for Experimental Evolution, Cold Spring Harbor, Long Island, New York. 1915-1923 (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence: Harris, J. Arthur, Department of Botany, University of Minnesota. 1925-1930 (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence: Blakeslee, A. F., Station for Experimental Evolution, Cold Spring Harbor, Long Island, New York. 1923-1937 (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence: Davenport, Charles B., Station for Experimental Evolution, Cold Spring Harbor, Long Island, New York. 1920-1929 (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence: Chaney, Ralph W., Long, Frances and Keck, David D. (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence: U. S. Navy Department regarding Helium. 1919-1923 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence: Free, Edward E. 1912-1934 (Box 13, Folder 2-5)
    - Free, Edward E. Articles. (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence: Cattell, J. McKeen (Editor, Science). 1905-1928 (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence: Science Service. 1920-1937 (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - Science Service, Minutes of Meetings. 1920-1930 (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Science Service, Financial Statements. 1922-1930 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - General Correspondence, 1907-1937
    - Correspondence: Ashby, Eric, England. 1930-1936 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence: Ayer, Edward E. 1921, 1923 (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence: Babcock, Ernest B., University of California Agricultural Experiment Station, Berkeley. 1921-1923 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence: Lesley, J. W., California. 1921-1923 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence: Bailey, L. H., Ithaca, New York. 1924, 1936-1937 (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence: Bakke, A. L., Department of Botany, Iowa State College. 1920-1937 (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence: Becking, L. B., Department of Botany, Stanford University. 1920-1929 (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence: Bowman, Isiah, American Geographical Society. 1921-1934 (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence: Britton, N. L., New York Botanical Garden. 1910-1928 (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence: Howe, Marshall, New York Botanical Garden. 1910-1928 (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence: Buxton, P. A., England. 1921-1931 (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence: Cahalane, Victor H., Cranbrook Institute of Science. 1932-1934 (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence: Carrel, Alexis, Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research. 1927 (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence: Castetter, E. F., Department of Botany, University of New Mexico. 1931-1937 (Box 14, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence: Clarke, Beverly L., Food Research Institute, Stanford University. 1924-1931 (Box 14, Folder 13)
    - Correspondence: Clowes, G. H. A., Eli Lilly and Co. 1920-1928 (Box 14, Folder 14)
    - Correspondence: Cole, A. C., Jr., U. S. D. A., Bureau of Entomology. 1932-1935 (Box 14, Folder 15)
    - Correspondence: Compton, R. H., National Botanic Gardens, Union of South Africa. 1929-1932 (Box 14, Folder 16)
    - Correspondence: Conkin, E. G., Department of Biology, Princeton, University. 1920-1925 (Box 14, Folder 17)
    - Correspondence: Cooper, William S., Department of Botany, University of Minnesota. 1920-1936 (Box 14, Folder 18)
    - Correspondence: Coulter, John M., Department of Botany, University of Chicago. 1907, 1920-1924, 1928-1929 (Box 14, Folder 19)
    - Correspondence: Coulter, Stanley, School of Science, Purdue University. 1921-1925 (Box 14, Folder 20)
    - Correspondence: Coville, Frederick V., (U. S. D. A., Bureau of Plant Industry. 1921, 1931-1936 (Box 14, Folder 21)
    - Correspondence: Czaja, A. T., Germany. 1923-1924 (Box 14, Folder 22)
    - Correspondence: Dean, Eva (artist). 1924-1934 (Box 14, Folder 23)
    - Correspondence: De Forest, H. W., New York Botanical Garden, Department of Botany, University of Southern California. 1928-1937 (Box 14, Folder 24)
    - Correspondence: Dellenbaugh, F. S. 1920-1930 (Box 14, Folder 25)
    - Correspondence: Dice, Lee R., Museum of Zoology, University of Michigan. 1928-1937 (Box 14, Folder 26)
    - Correspondence: Duggar, B. M., Missouri Botanical Garden, Department of Botany, University of Wisconsin. 1928-1937 (Box 14, Folder 27)
    - Correspondence: Emerson, Fred W., New Mexico Normal University. 1931-1933 (Box 14, Folder 28)
    - Correspondence: Farrand, Max, Huntington Library, regarding the cactus garden. 1929 (Box 14, Folder 29)
    - Correspondence: Fritsch, F. E., Department of Botany, University of London, England. 1929-1932 (Box 14, Folder 30)
    - Correspondence: Gager, C. Stuart, Brooklyn Botanical Garden. 1915-1929 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence: Gustafson, F. G., Department of Botany, University of Michigan. 1932-1937 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence: Harding, John W., American correspondent for the London Daily Chronicle. 1920-1929 (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence: Harper, R. A., Department of Botany, Columbia University, University of Alabama. 1920-1930 (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence: Harshberger, John W., Botany Department, University of Pennsylvania. 1920-1925 (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence: Hellmich, Walter, Zoologische Sammlung, Munchen, Germany. 1932-1933 (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence: Herrera, Alphonse L., Direccion de Estudios Biologicos, Mexico. 1920-1928 (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence: Hobbs, William H., Department of Geology, University of Michigan. 1924-1925 (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence: Hornaday, William T, New York Zoological Society. 1915-1929 (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence: Humphrey, Robert R., Department of Botany, University of Minnesota. 1930-1936 (Box 15, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence: Hunnington, Ellsworth, Yale University. 1912-1935 (Box 15, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence: Johnson, Duncan S., Botanical Garden and Lab, Johns Hopkins University. 1915-1937 (Box 15, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence: Jones, J. S., College of Engineering, University of Nevada. 1914-1915 (Box 15, Folder 13)
    - Correspondence: Killian, C., Lab de Botanique, University d'Alger, Algeria. 1930-1933 (Box 15, Folder 14)
    - Correspondence: Kinsey, Alfred C., Department of Zoology, Indiana University. 1920, 1925 (Box 15, Folder 15)
    - Correspondence: Lee, Frederic L., New York Botanical Garden. 1923-1929 (Box 15, Folder 16)
    - Correspondence: Livingston, Burton E., Lab of Plant Physiology, Johns Hopkins University. 1910-1937 (Box 15, Folder 17-19)
    - Correspondence: Lloyd, Francis E., Department of Botany, McGill University, Montreal. 1914-1932 (Box 15, Folder 20)
    - Correspondence: Long, Esmond R., University of Chicago, Henry Phipps Institute. 1920-1935 (Box 15, Folder 21)
    - Correspondence: Lotsy, J. P., Holland. 1922-1923 (Box 15, Folder 22)
    - Correspondence: McKee, Edwin, National Park Service. 1929-1934 (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence: Magnes, Judah L., Hebrew University, Palestine. 1931-1933 (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence: Mead, Pauline, Department of Botany, University of Chicago, National Park Service. 1929-1931 (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence: Menninger, C. F., Menninger Clinic, Kansas. 1932-1934 (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence: Merrill, Elmer D., Bureau of Science, Philippine Islands; New York Botanical Garden. 1914-1930 (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence: Meyer, Bernard S., Department of Botany, Ohio State University. 1928-1932 (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence: Moore, George T., Missouri Botanical Garden. 1913-1934 (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence: More, Louis T., University of Cincinnati. 1924-1925 (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence: National Research Council. 1921-1932 (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence: Overton, J. B., Department of Botany, University of Wisconsin. 1925-1932 (Box 16, Folder 10-11)
    - Correspondence: Parish, S. B., San Bernardino, California. 1913-1916 (Box 16, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence: Peirce, G. J., Department of Botany, Stanford University. 1913-1932 (Box 16, Folder 13)
    - Correspondence: Richards, Herbert M., Department of Botany, Barnard College, Columbia University. 1913-1929, 1937 (Box 16, Folder 14)
    - Correspondence: Schratz, E., Kaiser Wilhelm Institut fur Biologie, Berlin. 1927-1934 (Box 16, Folder 15)
    - Correspondence: Schroter, Carl, Zurich, Switzerland. 1914-1926 (Box 16, Folder 16)
    - Correspondence: Seifriz, William, Botanical Lab, University of Pennsylvania. 1922-1937 (Box 16, Folder 17)
    - Correspondence: Setchell, William A., Department of Botany, University of California, Berkley. 1913-1929 (Box 16, Folder 18)
    - Correspondence: Shull, George H., Department of Biology, Princeton University. 1913-1926 (Box 16, Folder 19)
    - Correspondence: Skottsberg, Carl, University of Upsala, Sweden. 1913, 1934-1935 (Box 16, Folder 20)
    - Correspondence: Small, J. K., New York Botanical Garden. 1920-1936 (Box 16, Folder 21)
    - Correspondence: Smith, Gilbert, Department of Botany, Stanford University. 1926-1929 (Box 16, Folder 22)
    - Correspondence: Snow, Laetitia M., Department of Botany, Wellesley College. 1920-1934 (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence: Thompson, William Boyce, Superior, Arizona. 1924-1925 (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence: Thompson, W. Gilman, New York. 1921-1927 (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence: Ulehla, Vladimir and Moravek, Vladimir, Institute for Plant Physiology, Masaryk University, Czechoslovakia. 1924-1928 (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence: Walter, Heinrich, Botanical Institute, Heidelberg and Stuttgart, Germany. 1929-1936 (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence: Weaver, J. E., Department of Botany, University of Nebraska. 1927-1935 (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence: Wilson, Edwin B., Department of Zoology, Columbia University, Department of Vital Statistics, Harvard University. 1920-1926 (Box 17, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence: Wright, John S., Eli Lilly and Co. 1921-1928 (Box 17, Folder 8)
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence. 1907, 1912-1937 (Box 17, Folder 9-11)
      Includes letters about a shipment of tortoises, May 6-10, 1924 and a letter from George Sarton, December 22, 1929.
    - Correspondence regarding soil analysis, temperature, moisture content, rain gauges, etc. 1929-1937 (Box 17, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence: Invitations. 1921-1935 (Box 17, Folder 13)
    - Correspondence: Carnegie Institution Exhibits. 1923-1935 (Box 17, Folder 14)
    - Correspondence from visitors. 1909-1937 (Box 17, Folder 15)
      Includes requests to visit the Laboratory, thank you notes, and information regarding the Desert Laboratory Tea, given by Dr. and Mrs. Shreve, April 3, 1929.
  - Guayule and Dendrograph Correspondence, 1912-1937
    - Miscellaneous correspondence on Guayule. 1913-1932 (Box 18, Folder 1)
      Includes letters to and from Cleveland Dodge, 1915 & 1920, and Russian professor N. Maximov in Leningrad.
    - Correspondence: Requests for Information on Guayule and rubber. 1913-1915 (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence: Dendograph patent and advertising. 1921-1924 (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - Miscellaneous correspondence on the Dendrograph. 1919-1932 (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence: Antes, Ernest American Geographical Society. 1923-1927 (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence: Bailey, I. W., Bussey Institution, Harvard University. 1919-1931 (Box 18, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence: Craighead, F. C., Department of Argiculture, Ottawa,; U. S. D. A, Bureau of Entomology. 1922-1926 (Box 18, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence: Dixon, Henry, H., School of Botany, Trinity College, Dublin. 1924-1929 (Box 18, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence: Korstian, C. F., U. S. D. A., Forest Service. 1920-1936 (Box 18, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence: McCallum, W. B., Rubber Exploration Co., California. 1912-1928 (Box 18, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence: Pearson, G. A., U. S. D. A., Forest Service. 1920-1936 (Box 18, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence: Pole-Evans, T. B., Division of Botany, Union of South Africa. 1920-1922 (Box 18, Folder 12)
      Includes a letter from Prime Minister, Jan Smuts.
    - Correspondence: Reed, H. S., Citrus Experiment Station, University of California, Riverside. 1919-1932 (Box 18, Folder 13)
    - Correspondence: Streets, Mrs. R. B., Tucson, Arizona. 1925-1927 (Box 18, Folder 14)
    - Correspondence: Sumner, F. B., Scripps Institution, University of California, La Jolla. 1920-1933 (Box 18, Folder 15)
    - Correspondence: Von Schrenk, Herman, Consulting Timber Engineer, St. Louis. 1913-1933 (Box 18, Folder 16)
    - Miscellaneous correspondence regarding McDougal's articles on the Dendograph and tree growth. 1919-1930 (Box 18, Folder 17)
      Includes letter from Gifford Pinchot, July 29, 1921.
  - Correspondence Regarding Plant Exchanges and Collecting, 1912-1937
    - Correspondence: Plant exchanges and collecting. 1912-1937 (Box 19, Folder 1-3)
    - Correspondence: Abrams, L. R., Dudley Herbarium, Stanford University. 1925-1937 (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence: Clayton, Alan B., San Diego & El Centro, California. 1933-1935 (Box 19, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence: Eig, A., Hebrew University, Palestine. 1931-1937 (Box 19, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence: Epling, Carl, University of California, Los Angeles. 1935-1937 (Box 19, Folder 6)